Guide to the Everett Cherrington Hughes Papers 1922-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Course Material
  - Subseries 7: Student Work
    - Peled, Uzi, field notes summary, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Poirier, Claude, autobiographical sketch, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Pope, Whitney, Sociology 448, "Detached Workers and Their Work," 1961 (Box 93, Folder 8)
    - Portnoy, Frances, Sociology 203C, "Congregation Beth El of Dorchester," 1965 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Reddy, Richard, "The Society of Jesus in New England: An Institution in Transition," 1968 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Riesman, Paul, "Preliminary Field Report on the Comparative Study of Child Rearing Among the Rimaaybe (ex-slaves) and the Fulani (ex-masters) in Upper Volta, West Africa," 1977 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - Roehrig, Albert, "Custodial vs. Professional Responsibility in the Culture of a Boarding School Faculty," 1957 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Ross, Michael, exams, papers, ca. 1977 (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Roth, Julius, "Supplementary Statement on the Journal of a Tuberculosis Hospital Attendant," n.d. (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Rubin, Miriam, field notes, interviews, 1963 (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Schwartz, Debbie, "The New York Urban Coalition," 1969 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Scott, John, "Race and Culture Contact in Southeastern Alaska: A Study of the Assimilation and Acculturation of the Wrangell Tlingit and White," Ph.D. dissertation abstract, 1952 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Shaw, Nancy, Boston Lying-in Hospital, field notes, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 2-3)
    - Shola, George, Sociology 351, paper on Romanian assimilation, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Sirois, Langis, "La carriËre des vendeurs de journeaux au kiosque," 1965 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Smith, David, "Transition Ceremonies and the Instrumental vs. Expressive Nature of Formal Volunteer Organizations: Further Test of a Cognitive Dissonance Hypothesis," ca. 1968 (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Sonn, Miriam, "The Boycott," 1968 (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Spector, Malcolm, "Commitment, Identification, and Career Contingencies," n.d. (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Stewart, Alice, night clubs, field notes 1966 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Stewart, Alice, "Audiences in Action: The Audience as Metaphor in Sociological Theory," n.d. (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Stoller, Nancy, "Reports and Realities," "A Study of Community Organizing," "The Ins and Outs of SNCC," 1964-1966 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Stone, Robert, Sociology 350, "Sociological Study of a Fraternity," ca. 1940 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - Whitby, Louise, "La situation des Canadiens-franÁais dans une industrie montrÈalaise," 1965 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - White, Ann, Social Science 432, "Inter-Racial Housing in Chicago," 1946 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Willner, Larry, "Twentieth Century Failure, Alan Ecks," 1963 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Wright, Sociology 400, term paper on Monteith College students, 1963 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - UniversitÈ Laval, student papers, 1943 (Box 95, Folder 4-5)
    - Sociology 325, student papers, 1952 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - McGill Seminar, student papers, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 120, student papers, 1970 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Field methods, "Social Areas of Charlestown," 1965 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Introduction to dissertation on seasonal laborers in northwestern U.S., n.d. (Box 95, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Writings and Research Material
  Series IV, Research and Writings, covers the period 1922-1980 and has been arranged into eight subseries: (1) Travel Diaries and Memoranda, (2) Research Materials, (3) Note Cards, ca. 1920s-1930s, (4) Translations, (5) Book Reviews, (6) Manuscripts, (7) Publishing Correspondence, (8) Publications.
  Subseries 1, Travel Diaries and Memoranda, has been arranged chronologically. Many of the memoranda are titled and concern places and topics including Japan and the bombing of Hiroshima, universities and education in the U.S. and abroad, professional meetings, and current social and political events.
  Subseries 2, Research Materials, is a group of miscellaneous projects with which Hughes was involved. The general areas in the files reflect Hughes's areas of study: race relations, occupations, and professions. They are loosely arranged by date and subject. The first is a student study of Bridgeport, (Chicago, Illinois) done in 1925-1926. Also included in this subseries are his work on the German Catholic labor movement and his work with the Committee on Human Relations in Industry. During his stay in Germany, Hughes collected German newspapers following the rise of the Nazi party, which are housed in Oversize Boxes 145-147. A travel diary with notes from Frankfurt in 1948 is filed in subseries 2, because this travel diary served as a basis for a lecture and published essay entitled "Good People and Dirty Work." This subseries also contains material relating to a National Opinion Research Center study on American priests done in 1970-1971.
  The note cards in subseries 3 were generated in his student days at the University of Chicago. In his memoranda entitled "On My Years in Graduate School at the University of Chicago, 29 January 1976," Hughes describes the system: note cards are in the "4 x 6" slips after the W. I. Thomas scheme. The manuscript being on white, bibliography being on blue and quotations being on orange colored slips.
  There is a small group of translations by Hughes arranged alphabetically by author in subseries 4. Subseries 5, Book Reviews, is reviews written by Hughes. The reviews date from 1926 to 1979 and are arranged chronologically.
  Subseries 6, Manuscripts, includes published and unpublished manuscripts, addresses, and magazine articles. These materials are arranged chronologically. Included with this subseries are some of the files generated by the project undertaken by Hughes, Winifred Raushenbush, and others to publish the papers of Robert Park. Hughes gave most of these files to the University of Chicago Library where they are now part of the Robert Park Papers in the Department of Special Collections.
  Subseries 7, Publishing Correspondence, has been arranged chronologically and consists of reviews of his work, requests for reprints, publishing contracts, and correspondence regarding the publication of some of Hughesís older titles such as the Chicago Real Estate Board and French Canada in Transition. Similar letters can be found in Series II.
  Subseries 8, Publications, is made up of reprints and smaller books, one of them a private publication done here at the University of Chicago entitled Cases on Field Work co-authored by Everett C. Hughes, Buford H. Junker, Ray L. Gold, and Dorothy Kittel. These are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 1: Travel Diaries and Memoranda
    - Germany, correspondence, 1931-1934 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Germany, annotated calendar, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Quebec trailer trip with the Park family, diary, August 1936 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Germany, diary, correspondence, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Moscow, diary, tourist pamphlets, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Moscow, correspondence, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Moscow, International Sociological Association, Conference on Peaceful Cooperation, notes, memoranda, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Germany, Italy, memoranda, correspondence, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Prague, memoranda, notes, 1958 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Japan, correspondence, record of presentation books, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Japan, diary notes, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Japan, annotated calendar, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Japan, lecture notes, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 13-14)
    - Japan, seminar notes, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - Japan, meeting about the bombing of Hiroshima, 1945, report, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - Japan, diary, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 17-18)
    - Japan, address book, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 19)
    - Korea, correspondence, lecture notes, names, addresses, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - England, diary, summer 1964 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - "A Memorandum on Canada, Cuba and the USA," February 1962 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Yugoslavia, memoranda, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - New Delhi, India, memoranda, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - New Delhi, Third World Congress on Medical Education, notes, November 15-25, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - England, memoranda, December 1971-January 1972 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - England, "notes on conversations and observations," 1972 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - England, notes, 1975 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Memoranda, notes, pre-1960 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - "Family and Land: A Document Based On Observations in an Ohio Rural Community," 1945 (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - "Morning after Fantasy on Night before Reality, with Counterpoint on Two Themes, `Sociology Begins at Home,' and `Let Us Not Be Static in Our View,'" February 1, 1952 (Box 97, Folder 11)
    - "Meeting with Dean George Waggoner of the College of Liberal Arts, KU," May 23, 1958 (Box 97, Folder 12)
    - "Getting Access to the Field," 1959 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - "French Politics," August 29, 1960 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Memoranda, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 15)
    - "A Deviant Student," "The Student Condition," 1963 (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - "A Turning Point at Ohio Wesleyan University," memorandum, April 18, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 17)
    - Teaching of field work, memoranda, notes, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - Memoranda, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 19)
    - "Meeting of Sociologists of the State of Mississippi, Tougaloo College," March 13-14, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 20)
    - "Memorandum on Students and Universities," London, August 20, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 21)
    - French-Canada, memoranda, 1965 (Box 97, Folder 22)
    - Sociolinguistics, memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 97, Folder 23)
    - Memoranda, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 24)
    - "Notes on a Visit to Oxford, Mississippi," May 13-14, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 25)
    - "The Rockefeller University," 1966 (Box 97, Folder 26)
    - Memoranda, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 27)
    - "An Academic Week," June 5-12, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 28)
    - "Memorandum Concerning Summer Institute at the University of Calgary," June 21, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 29)
    - "Post-Mortem on the Session Devoted to Personal Experience of Race," American Sociological Association, San Francisco, August 31, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 30)
    - "Memorandum on Virginia Woolf's A Room of One's Own," 1967 (Box 97, Folder 31)
    - Arab-Israel War, 1967 (Box 97, Folder 32)
    - "Confidential Notes on Boston College," 1968-1969 (Box 97, Folder 33)
    - Siena College, Memphis, Tennessee, March 29-30, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 34)
    - "Memorandum on the Assassination of Robert Kennedy," June 7 or 8, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 35)
    - "St. Jean Baptiste Parade in Montreal," June 24, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 36)
    - "Confidential Notes on the Foundation Man Project," New York, October 10, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 37)
    - "Notes on the University of Alabama, Tuscaloosa," November 10, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - "Memo on Study of Contemporary Society," February 1968 (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Memoranda, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - "Notes on a Visit to Cedar Crest College," February 18, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - "Memorandum Concerning Canadian University Convocations," June 2, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - "Memorandum on Repatriation of Immigrants and on Racialism in Britain," England, June 22, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - "Memorandum on the Modern Economy and Its Labor Force," England, July 12, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - "Memorandum on Terrorism in Quebec," August 21, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - "Memorandum on R. E. Park and the Earlier Sociologists at Chicago with Reference to Racial Problems and Especially Negroes," December 6, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Memoranda, 1970 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Quebec, Canada, memoranda, 1970 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Exchange of notes and letters on the sociological enterprise, Talcott Parsons, David Riesman, 1970 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - "Concerning Sidney Spivak," memorandum, December 1970 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Memoranda, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - "Memorandum on Chien Blanc" by Gary Romain, August 10, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - "The Ecology of Boston College," November 11, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Memoranda, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - "Report of a Session of the Canadian Association of Sociologists and Anthropologists, Montreal, May 31, 1972," June 7, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - "Boston and Chicago," memoranda, notes, 1972-1978 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - "Memorandum on the Meeting of the Society for Applied Anthropology held in Montreal at the Mount Royal Hotel, April 6 to 9, 1972," memorandum, lecture, April 9, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Presidential campaign, memoranda, correspondence, 1972 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Memoranda, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - "Memorandum, The Retirement of a Bishop," August 20, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - Memoranda, 1974 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - "Memorandum on the Olfactory Bubble," October 24, 1974 (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - Memoranda, 1975 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - "Concerning Raushenbush's Biography, Entitled, The Natural History of the Mind of Robert E. Park," March 24, 1975 (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - Memoranda, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Quebec, memoranda, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - "On Going to School in Chicago," memorandum, February 2, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 30)
    - "Notes Growing Out of the AAAS Meeting in Boston, February 19, 1976. The notes also grow out of other notes I have been making about my time as a graduate student and the history of sociology and social science in general," 1976 (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - "The Baptist Cathedral in Plains, Georgia," memorandum, notes, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - "Material for a General Book in Sociology," January 7, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 33)
    - "Notes on So-called Higher Education," February 4, 1976 (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - Memoranda, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Quebec, memoranda, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - "Memorandum on the Journal Social Problems, Volume 24, No. 1, October 1976," March 16, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - "The Life Cycle of an Institution and the Social Gospel Movement. Notes on Herbert Welch, As I Recall My Past Century," June 17, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda, 1978 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Memoranda, 1979 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Quebec, memoranda, 1979 (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - "Communication in a Language in a Country with Two or More Languages," March 19, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 2: Research Materials
    - Bridgeport, Illinois, interviews, notes, 1925-1926 (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - "Bridgeport," report, 1926 (Box 99, Folder 10)
    - Dutch and German 17th-19th century economic institutions, notes, ca. 1930 (Box 99, Folder 11)
    - Germany, Catholic labor movement, interviews, statistics, manuscripts, 1931-1932 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Germany, Catholic labor movement, notes, statistics, manuscripts, 1931-1933 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Germany, Catholic labor movement, statistics, notes, 1931-1933 (Box 99, Folder 14-15)
    - Germany, Catholic labor movement, German pamphlets, 1910-1931 (Box 99, Folder 16-17)
    - Germany, Catholic labor movement, German handbills, pamphlets, ca. 1927-1932 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Germany, German pamphlets, 1922, 1931 (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - Germany, rise of the Nazi party, German broadsides, pamphlets, ca. 1931-1932 (Box 99, Folder 20)
    - Germany, rise of the Nazi party, American, Canadian, and German newspaper clippings, 1932-1933 (Box 99, Folder 21)
    - Germany, World War II propaganda, U.S. publications, 1939-1940 (Box 99, Folder 22)
    - Germany, World War II propaganda, map of Germany and Poland, (oversize) September and December 1939 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Germany, Frankfurt diary, Spring 1948 (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Germany, memoranda, 1948 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Germany, memoranda, mores of misery, 1948 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Germany, memoranda, politics, 1948 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Germany, memoranda, university, 1948 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Germany, memoranda, university and students, 1948 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Germany, proposed manuscripts, outlines, notes, ca. 1948 (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Germany, "Innocents Abroad, 1948 or How to Behave in Occupied Germany," 1948 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - "Proceedings of the Seminar on Racial and Cultural Contacts," University of Chicago, 1935-1936 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, notes, manuscripts, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 1. general introduction and theory, notes, manuscripts, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 2. review and critique of other studies, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 4. sociology of industry, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 4. sociology of industry, "An Experiment in Changing Employee Morale," manuscript, ca. 1945 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 4. sociology of industry, Committee on Human Relations in Industry, remarks, April 10, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 4. sociology of industry, President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice, regional conference, comments, agenda, March 25, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 15)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 4. sociology of industry, Mary Jo Rendleman, "Interview with Mr. R., personnel manager of a garment factory, Michigan City, Indiana," July 9, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 16)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 5. types of industries and plants, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 17)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 6. types of workers (where Negroes are found), 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 18)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 7. segregation and discrimination, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 11. Negro relations to whites in industry, interviews, notes, papers, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 20)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 12. Negro relations to Negroes in industry, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 21)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 14. comparative framework, notes, 1944-1945 (Box 100, Folder 22)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 14. comparative framework, "Racial and Ethnic Relations in Industry," lecture, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 23)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 15. racial incidents (dynamics of racial etiquette), report, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 24)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, 16. "passing," Negroes and social orientation, interviews, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 25)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, neighborhood information and attitudes towards Negroes, interview, ca. 1945 (Box 100, Folder 26)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, distribution of Negroes in plants, notes, 1931, 1944 (Box 100, Folder 27)
    - Committee on Human Relations in Industry, Race Relations in Industry, Visking Corporation, the shirring room, interviews, 1945 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Race and culture, reading notes, ca. 1941-1945 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Race relations, schools and race, Young Men's Business Club of New Orleans, reports, 1955 (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Race relations, South Africa, reprints, 1945-1967 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Race relations, The People's Forum, "Myrdal's An American Dilemma," Parkway Community House, Chicago, September-November 1945 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Race relations, Amerika Haus, notes, 1948 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Race relations, minorities in Canada and Germany, ca. 1950s (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - Race relations, new peoples, notes, ca. 1954 (Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Race relations, letters from Bob Levine in Africa to David Riesman, 1956-1957 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Race relations, Mozel Hill, "The Negro Man and His Work," interviews, manuscripts, ca. 1961 (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - Race relations, American Negro movement, Liberation, statement by the editors, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - Race relations, Testimony of Herbert Hill, Labor Secretary, NAACP, before the U.S. Department of Labor public hearing, November 5, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Race relations, Mission Hill incident, stoning of windows of Negro tenant, Boston, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - Race relations, "Transcript of the Negro in America Planning Committee," sponsored by Daedalus, House of the Academy, Boston, MA, April 10-11, 1964 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - Race relations, Great Britain, papers, 1965 (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - Race relations, Black Studies, papers, correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - Race relations, race in Europe, memoranda, 1969 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Race relations, Moynihan-Nixon racial pronouncements, Hughes-Riesman correspondence, memoranda, March 1970 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Race relations, miscellaneous, notes, papers, correspondence, documents, 1926-1971 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Race relations, miscellaneous, notes, papers, 1954-1970 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Race relations, miscellaneous, notes, papers, reprints, 1953-1969 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Race relations, miscellaneous, papers, 1962-1968 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Race relations, unidentified, "Chapter 15, Conclusions," nationalism in Iraq, manuscript, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Race relations, notes, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Race relations, politics, notes, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Ecology of institutions, notes, ca. 1935 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Institutions, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Institutions, notes, n.d. (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - "A Proposal for Study of the Dynamics of Rural Culture and Institutions," 1945 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - "Work Careers," report, abstract, notes, 1954 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Professions, notes, 1930s-1940s (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Professions, control codes, notes, 1930s-1940s (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Professions, the client, notes, ca. 1940s (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Professions, natural history, notes, ca. 1942 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Professions, colleagueship, notes, ca. 1942 (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Professions, notes, ca. 1949 (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Professions, "Material for the Report of the Radcliffe-MGH Project," February 13, 1958 (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Professions, "Freie Berufe," Sozialwissenschaften, notes, correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Professions, technique and knowledge, notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Professions, professions in literature, notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Professions, communication and secrecy at work, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Work and occupations, dirty work, notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Voluntary associations, notes, 1942 (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - Social movements, notes, papers, correspondence, 1955-1961 (Box 103, Folder 15)
    - Social movements, conflict, politics, papers, notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 16)
    - Definition of situation, notes, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 17)
    - Education, notes, 1959 (Box 103, Folder 18)
    - Education, notes, 1971-1978 (Box 103, Folder 19)